Guide to the Amber Arthun Warburton Papers, 1917-1976 and undated RL.01341
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Institute of Social and Religious Research Series, 1929-1930
  - United States Children's Bureau Series, 1929-1944
    - Alliance for Guidance of Rural Youth Series, 1922-1966
      Material in the collection is arranged by subject, and within subject by type (correspondence, printed material, etc.) The subjects are not arranged alphabetically or chronologically, so researchers should carefully study the subject entries for the entire series before plunging into the material. Also there is considerable overlapping of material in the series. For instance, correspondence from Glyn Morris of Harlan County, Kentucky, could be found under Harlan County or under Board of Trustees, depending on the subject. Consequently, researchers should expect to examine several subject headings if the topic is broad.
      Once the inventory is studied, researchers will find rich sources of information on socioeconomic conditions in several rural or rural-industrial communities: Harlan County, Kentucky, Green Sea, South Carolina, and Belle Glade, Florida. Much of the work done in these and other communities was compressed into terse, lucid studies that can be found under the heading "Publications" in boxes 26 and 27. There is also much material on the day-to-day operations of several guidance organizations: Alliance for Guidance of Rural Youth, Council of Guidance and Personnel Associations, and the National Council of Agricultural Life and Labor.
      - Index to Office Files (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Constitution, By-Laws, and Certificate of Incorporation (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Board of Trustees
        - Fund Committee,1949-1951 (Box 23, Folder 4)
        - Correspondence, 1949-1966 (Box 23, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence. Mrs. Virginia Claiborne, 1950-1956 (Box 23, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence. Orie Latham Hatcher Memorial Plaque, 1949-1950 (Box 23, Folder 7)
        - Correspondence. Ruth Strang, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 8)
        - Correspondence. Ruth Strang, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 9)
        - Correspondence. Ruth Strang, 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 10)
        - Correspondence: Ruth Strang, 1952-1958 (Box 23, Folder 11)
        - Correspondence. Alice Baldwin, 1949-1958 (Box 24, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence. Chicago Branch, 1948-1950 (Box 24, Folder 2)
        - Minutes and Accompanying Material, 1947-1949 (Box 24, Folder 3)
        - Minutes and Accompanying Material, 1950-1952 (Box 24, Folder 4)
        - Minutes and Accompanying Material, 1953-1963 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Pre-1947Material
        - Correspondence, 1936-1946 (Box 24, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence. Information Requests, 1941-1946 (Box 24, Folder 7)
        - Notes of Orie Latham Hatcher, 1934-1944 (Box 24, Folder 8)
        - Reports, Memoranda, and Lists, 1930-1946 (Box 24, Folder 9)
        - Minutes and Accompanying Material from the Board of Trustees, 1946 (Box 24, Folder 10)
        - Programs for Institutes, 1941-1944 (Box 24, Folder 11)
        - Clippings. Orie Latham Hatcher Obituaries and Other Clippings (Box 24, Folder 12)
        - Printed Material, 1922-1929 (Box 25, Folder 1, Box 81)
        - Printed Material, 1930-1931 (Box 25, Folder 2)
        - Printed Material, 1935-1936 (Box 25, Folder 3)
        - Printed Material, 1942-1946 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Appeals to Foundations
        - Correspondence and Accompanying Material, 1948-1952 (Box 25, Folder 5)
        - Appeal to the Kellogg Foundation, 1947-1948 (Box 25, Folder 6)
        - Appeal to the General Education Board, 1948 (Box 25, Folder 7)
        - Appeal to the Farm Foundation, 1948-1949 (Box 25, Folder 8)
        - Appeal to the Farm Foundation, 1951 (Box 25, Folder 9)
        - Volume. Exhibit Materials for Appeals to Foundations (Box 26)
      - Invitations to Join Organizations and Appeals for Money, 1948-1954 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Lists, 1947-1954 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Lists. Registration Cards, 1950 and undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Publications
        - Miscellany, 1937-1946 (Box 81, Box 26, Folder 4)
        - Volumes. A Mountain School (1930), Rural Girls in the City for Work (1930),and The Need for Guidance Programs in Privately Supported Mountain Schools (Box 26)
        - Miscellany, 1947-1948 (Box 27, Folder 1)
        - Miscellany, 1949-1951 (Box 27, Folder 2)
        - Volumes. Migratory Labor in American Agriculture (1951), The Education of Migrant Children (1954), Guidance in a Rural-Industrial Community (1954),and Stimulating Guidance in Rural Schools (1964) (Box 27)
        - Alliance Memberships. Correspondence, 1949-1953 (Box 27, Folder 3)
        - Alliance Memberships. Membership Form Letters (Box 27, Folder 4)
        - Alliance Memberships. Lists, 1949-1950 (Box 27, Folder 5)
        - Alliance Memberships. Index Card File, 1948-1950 (Box 27, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence, 1947-1954 (Box 27, Folder 7)
        - Correspondence. Publications, 1947-1949 (Box 27, Folder 8)
        - Correspondence. Publications, 1950-1951 (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - Bibliographic Material, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 2)
        - Publicity, 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 3)
        - Scholarships. Orie Latham Hatcher, 1947-1950 (Box 28, Folder 4)
        - Scholarships. Exeter Academy, 1948-1950 (Box 28, Folder 5)
        - Scholarships. MacMurray College, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 6)
        - Executive Secretary. Notice of Employment,1947 (Box 28, Folder 7)
        - Annual Institute. Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 8)
        - Annual Institute. Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 9)
        - Annual Institute. Program and Transcript, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 10)
        - Meetings. 32nd Annual, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 11)
        - Meetings. 33rd Annual, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 12)
        - Meetings. 35th Annual, 1950 (Box 28, Folder 13)
        - Discussions and Conferences, 1949 (Box 29, Folder 1)
        - Discussions and Conferences, 1951 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Council of Guidance and Personnel Associations
        In 1952 the CGPA changed its name to American Personnel and Guidance Association. Consequently, all material from 1952 and after should be under the heading APGA, but for ease of organization, the material from the APGA has remained under the heading CGPA.
        - Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 3)
        - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 29, Folder 4)
        - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 29, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 30, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 2)
        - Correspondence and Notes, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 3)
        - Correspondence and Notes, 1954-1955 (Box 30, Folder 4)
        - Convention Material
          - 1947-1948 (Box 30, Folder 5)
          - 1949 (Box 30, Folder 6)
          - 1950 (Box 30, Folder 7)
          - 1951 (Box 30, Folder 8)
          - 1952 (Box 31, Folder 1)
          - 1953 (Box 31, Folder 2)
          - 1954 (Box 31, Folder 3)
          - 1960-1966 (Box 31, Folder 4)
        - Board of Representatives. Meeting Minutes, 1947-1949 (Box 31, Folder 5)
        - Board of Representatives. Meeting Minutes, 1950-1954 (Box 31, Folder 6)
        - Study Commission. Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 31, Folder 7)
        - Study Commission. Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 31, Folder 8)
        - Study Commission. Assorted Material, 1948-1950 (Box 32, Folder 1)
        - Newsletters. The Guidepost, 1960-1963 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - National Vocational Guidance Association, 1950-1955 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Luncheon-Forum. Correspondence,1947-1948 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Luncheon-Forum. Correspondence, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Luncheon-Forum. Lists, 1947-1949 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Luncheon-Forum. Miscellany, 1947-1949 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Information Requests
        - 1947 (Box 32, Folder 8)
        - 1948 (Box 33, Folder 1)
        - 1949, Jan. - Aug. (Box 33, Folder 2)
        - 1949, Sept. - Dec. (Box 33, Folder 3)
        - 1950, Jan. - May (Box 33, Folder 4)
        - 1950, June - Dec. (Box 33, Folder 5)
        - 1951 (Box 33, Folder 6)
        - 1952-1954 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - Change of Address. Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Reprint Acknowledgements, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Harlan County
        In 1947 the Alliance for Guidance of Rural Youth helped the people of Harlan County, Kentucky, set up programs to deal with educational and vocational guidance, health, nutrition, child welfare, and the prevention of juvenile delinquency. The programs were a county-wide continuation of a much smaller guidance and health program started at the Pine Mountain Settlement School in 1935. Material from Harlan County is divided into three broad categories: Guidance Institutes, community programs generated by the Institutes, and material related to the book written about the work in Harlan County, Guidance in a Rural-Industrial Community. A copy of the book is in Box 27.
        - Guidance Institute, 1947
          - Correspondence, 1947, July 1-15 (Box 34, Folder 3)
          - Correspondence, 1947, July 16-31 (Box 34, Folder 4)
          - Correspondence, 1947, Aug.-Dec. - 1948, Jan. (Box 34, Folder 5)
          - Press Releases (Box 34, Folder 6)
          - Program (Box 34, Folder 7)
          - Reports and Speeches (Box 34, Folder 8)
          - Reports and Surveys (Box 34, Folder 9)
          - Notes (Box 34, Folder 10)
          - Clippings (Box 35, Folder 1)
        - Guidance Institute, 1948
          - Correspondence (Box 35, Folder 2)
          - Programs and Reports (Box 35, Folder 3)
          - Notes and Clippings (Box 35, Folder 4)
        - Guidance Institute, 1949
          - Correspondence (Box 35, Folder 5)
          - Programs and Reports (Box 35, Folder 6)
          - Notes and Clippings (Box 35, Folder 7)
        - Guidance Institute, 1950. Miscellany (Box 35, Folder 8)
        - Guidance Institute, 1951. Program (Box 35, Folder 9)
        - Guidance Institute, 1953.Program (Box 35, Folder 10)
        - Correspondence. Glyn Morris, 1947-1949 (Box 35, Folder 11)
        - Questionnaires on Youth Guidance Programs, no. 1-100 (Box 35, Folder 12)
        - Questionnaires on Youth Guidance Programs, no. 101-175 (Box 36, Folder 1)
        - Student Essays
          - Benham High School, 11th Grade (Box 36, Folder 2)
          - Benham High School, 12th Grade (Box 36, Folder 3)
          - Black Star High School, 11th Grade (Box 36, Folder 4)
          - Black Star High School, 12th Grade (Box 36, Folder 5)
          - Cumberland High School, 11th Grade (Box 36, Folder 6)
          - Cumberland High School, 12th Grade (Box 36, Folder 7)
          - Evarts High School, 11th Grade (Box 36, Folder 8)
          - Evarts High School, 12th Grade (Box 36, Folder 9)
          - Hall High School, 11th Grade (Box 36, Folder 10)
          - Hall High School, 11th Grade (Box 36, Folder 11)
          - Hall High School, 11th Grade (Box 37, Folder 1)
          - Loyall High School, 11th Grade (Box 37, Folder 2)
          - Loyall High School, 12th Grade (Box 37, Folder 3)
          - Wallins High School, 11th Grade (Box 37, Folder 4)
          - Wallins High School, 12th Grade (Box 37, Folder 5)
        - Student Essays on Harlan County History
          - 7th Grade (Box 37, Folder 6)
          - 7th Grade (Box 37, Folder 7)
          - 7th Grade (Box 37, Folder 8)
          - 10th Grade (Box 37, Folder 9)
          - 10th Grade (Box 37, Folder 10)
        - Student Histories
          - Ages School, 6th Grade (Box 38, Folder 1)
          - Benham School, 6th Grade (Box 38, Folder 2)
          - Benham School, 8th Grade (Box 38, Folder 3)
          - Benham High School, 9th Grade (Box 38, Folder 4)
          - Black Mountain School, 6th Grade (Box 38, Folder 5)
          - Black Star School, 6th Grade (Box 38, Folder 6)
          - Black Star School, 7th Grade (Box 38, Folder 7)
          - Black Star School, 8th Grade (Box 38, Folder 8)
          - Black Star School, 9th Grade (Box 38, Folder 9)
          - Cawood School, 8th Grade (Box 38, Folder 10)
          - Chad School, 5th Grade (Box 38, Folder 11)
          - Chevrolet School, 8th Grade (Box 38, Folder 12)
          - Coxton School, 6th Grade (Box 38, Folder 13)
          - Coxton School, 8th Grade (Box 38, Folder 14)
          - Cranks School, 5th Grade (Box 39, Folder 1)
          - Cranks School, 6th Grade (Box 39, Folder 2)
          - Cumberland School, 6th Grade (Box 39, Folder 3)
          - Cumberland School, 8th Grade (Box 39, Folder 4)
          - Cumberland High School, 9th Grade (Box 39, Folder 5)
          - Dixie Town School, 6th Grade (Box 39, Folder 6)
          - Dixie Town School, 8th Grade (Box 39, Folder 7)
          - Elcomb School, 6th Grade (Box 39, Folder 8)
          - Evarts School, 6th Grade (Box 39, Folder 9)
          - Evarts School, 8th Grade (Box 39, Folder 10)
          - Evarts High School, 9th Grade (Box 40, Folder 1)
          - Evarts High School, 9th Grade (Box 40, Folder 2)
          - Evarts High School, 9th Grade (Box 40, Folder 3)
          - High Bank School, 6th Grade (Box 40, Folder 4)
          - High Bank School, 8th Grade (Box 40, Folder 5)
          - Highsplint School, 6th Grade (Box 40, Folder 6)
          - Highsplint School, 8th Grade (Box 40, Folder 7)
          - Kentenia School, 6th Grade (Box 40, Folder 8)
          - Kentenia School, 7th Grade (Box 40, Folder 9)
          - Louellen School, 6th Grade (Box 40, Folder 10)
          - Louellen School, 8th Grade (Box 40, Folder 11)
          - Loyall School, 6th Grade (Box 41, Folder 1)
          - Loyall School, 7th Grade (Box 41, Folder 2)
          - Loyall School, 8th Grade (Box 41, Folder 3)
          - Loyall High School, 9th Grade (Box 41, Folder 4)
          - Mary Helen School, 6th Grade (Box 41, Folder 5)
          - Mary Helen School, 8th Grade (Box 41, Folder 6)
          - Molus School, 6th Grade (Box 41, Folder 7)
          - Molus School, 8th Grade (Box 41, Folder 8)
          - Pine Flat School, 6th Grade (Box 41, Folder 9)
          - Pine Mountain School, 6th Grade (Box 41, Folder 10)
          - Pine Mountain School, 7th Grade (Box 41, Folder 11)
          - Pine Mountain School, 8th Grade (Box 41, Folder 12)
          - Pine Mountain School, 9th Grade (Box 41, Folder 13)
          - Putney School, 6th Grade (Box 41, Folder 14)
          - Putney School, 7th Grade (Box 41, Folder 15)
          - Ross Point School, 5th Grade (Box 41, Folder 16)
          - Ross Point School, 6th Grade (Box 41, Folder 17)
          - Ross Point School, 8th Grade (Box 41, Folder 18)
          - Shields School, 6th Grade (Box 41, Folder 19)
          - Shields School, 7th Grade (Box 41, Folder 20)
          - Shields School, 8th Grade (Box 41, Folder 21)
          - Smith School, 6th Grade (Box 41, Folder 22)
          - Smith School, 8th Grade (Box 41, Folder 23)
          - Totz School, 6th Grade (Box 41, Folder 24)
          - Totz School, 8th Grade (Box 41, Folder 25)
          - Twila School, 5th Grade (Box 42, Folder 1)
          - Twila School, 6th Grade (Box 42, Folder 2)
          - Twila School, 8th Grade (Box 42, Folder 3)
          - Verda School, 5th Grade (Box 42, Folder 4)
          - Verda School, 6th Grade (Box 42, Folder 5)
          - Verda School, 8th Grade (Box 42, Folder 6)
          - Wallins School, 6th Grade (Box 42, Folder 7)
          - Wallins School, 7th Grade (Box 42, Folder 8)
          - Wallins School, 8th Grade (Box 42, Folder 9)
          - Wallins School, 9th Grade (Box 42, Folder 10)
          - White Star School, 4th Grade (Box 42, Folder 11)
          - White Star School, 5th Grade (Box 42, Folder 12)
          - White Star School, 7th Grade (Box 42, Folder 13)
          - Yancey School, 6th Grade (Box 42, Folder 14)
        - Teachers' Progress Reports
          - No. 1-20 (Box 42, Folder 15)
          - No. 21-40 (Box 42, Folder 16)
          - No. 41-60 (Box 43, Folder 1)
          - No. 61-80 (Box 43, Folder 2)
          - No. 81-100 (Box 43, Folder 3)
          - No. 101-120 (Box 43, Folder 4)
          - No. 121-140 (Box 43, Folder 5)
          - No. 141-160 (Box 44, Folder 1)
          - No. 161-180 (Box 44, Folder 2)
          - No. 181-200 (Box 44, Folder 3)
          - No. 202-219 (Box 44, Folder 4)
          - No. 221-240 (Box 44, Folder 5)
          - No. 241-260 (Box 44, Folder 6)
          - No. 261-280 (Box 45, Folder 1)
          - No. 281-300 (Box 45, Folder 2)
          - No. 301-320a (Box 45, Folder 3)
          - No. 321-330 (Box 45, Folder 4)
        - Principal's Progress Reports, No. 1-a (Box 45, Folder 5)
        - File on Jean High, 1946 (Box 45, Folder 6)
        - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 45, Folder 7)
        - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 45, Folder 8)
        - Miscellaneous Notes and Printed Material (Box 46, Folder 1)
        - Clippings, 1950 and undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
        - Photographs. Youth Guidance Institute, 1948 (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Photographs. (Box 46, Folder 4)
          Some of the photographs in this and the following folders were published in Warburton's Guidance in a Rural-Industrial Community. Negatives are in the Negative File.
        - Photographs (Box 46, Folder 5)
        - Photographs (Box 46, Folder 6)
        - Photographs (Box 46, Folder 7)
        - Volumes. Scrapbooks, 1947 and 1948 (Box 47)
        - Material Related to Guidance in a Rural-Industrial Community
          - Correspondence, 1952-1955 (Box 47, Folder 1)
          - Publicity, 1954 (Box 47, Folder 2)
          - Reviews (Box 47, Folder 3)
          - Photographs and Maps on Galley Sheets (Box 47, Folder 4)
          - Volumes. Drafts of book (Box 47)
          - Volumes. Drafts of book (Box 48)
        - Breathitt County, Kentucky. Correspondence and Accompanying Material, 1948-1951 (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Fairfax County, Virginia. Correspondence and Accompanying Material, 1948-1949 (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - Virginia State Department of Education. Correspondence and Accompanying Material, 1950 (Box 81, Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Green Sea
        In 1949 the Alliance for Guidance of Rural Youth helped the people in the Green Sea School District in northern Horry County, South Carolina, set up programs to deal with educational and vocational guidance, health, nutrition, child welfare, and the prevention of juvenile delinquency. Material from Green Sea is arranged differently than material from Harlan County: papers from the Youth Guidance Institute are not separated from the community-generated material, but rather incorporated within it. Material related to the book written about the work in Green Sea, Guidance in a Rural Community, is at the end of the papers from Green Sea. Although there is no copy of the book in the collection, there are several complete manuscripts. A copy is available in the East Campus Library.
        - Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 49, Folder 4)
        - Correspondence,1949 (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence,1950 (Box 49, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence,1951 (Box 49, Folder 7)
        - Correspondence and Notes, 1952-1955 (Box 50, Folder 1)
        - Project Plans and Accompanying Material (Box 50, Folder 2)
        - Census Data (Box 50, Folder 3)
        - Preliminary Reports, 1948-1949 (Box 50, Folder 4)
        - Youth Guidance Institute, 1949
          - Program and Accompanying Material (Box 50, Folder 5)
          - Recommendations of Discussion Groups. Bayboro School - Grassy Bay School (Box 50, Folder 6)
          - Recommendations of Discussion Groups. Green Sea Schools (Box 50, Folder 7)
          - Recommendations of Discussion Groups. Hickory Hill School - Zoan School (Box 50, Folder 8)
          - Follow-Up to Institute (Box 50, Folder 9)
        - Principals' Progress Reports, No. 1-5 (Box 50, Folder 10)
        - Teachers' Progress Reports, No. 1-15 (Box 51, Folder 1)
        - Teachers' Progress Reports, No. 16-20 (Box 51, Folder 2)
        - Teachers' Reports on the Health Program, No. 1-41 (Box 51, Folder 3)
        - Miscellaneous Reports and Surveys, 1948-1953 (Box 51, Folder 4)
        - Community Planning Council, 1948-1951 (Box 51, Folder 5)
        - Health Program, 1949-1950 (Box 51, Folder 6)
        - Negro Program, 1950 (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Primary School Teachers' Group, 1950 (Box 51, Folder 8)
        - Community Survey of Children and Youth
          - Bethany School (Box 51, Folder 9)
          - Carolina School (Box 51, Folder 10)
          - Finklea School (Box 52, Folder 1)
          - Fowler School (Box 52, Folder 2)
          - Grassy Bay School (Box 52, Folder 3)
          - Green Sea Elementary School (Box 52, Folder 4)
          - Green Sea High School (Box 52, Folder 5)
          - Hickory Hill School (Box 52, Folder 6)
          - Norton School (Box 52, Folder 7)
          - Powell School (Box 52, Folder 8)
          - Zoan School (Box 53, Folder 1)
          - Non-District Schools (Box 53, Folder 2)
          - School Dropouts (Box 53, Folder 3)
          - Partial Statistical Summary (Box 53, Folder 4)
        - Health Program Survey
          - Bayboro School (Box 53, Folder 5)
          - Bethany School (Box 53, Folder 6)
          - Carolina School (Box 53, Folder 7)
          - Finklea School (Box 53, Folder 8)
          - Fowler School (Box 53, Folder 9)
          - Grassy Bay School (Box 53, Folder 10)
          - Green Sea High School (Box 53, Folder 11)
          - Hickory Hill School (Box 53, Folder 12)
          - Norton School (Box 53, Folder 13)
          - Powell School (Box 54, Folder 1)
          - Zoan School (Box 54, Folder 2)
          - Statistical Summary (Box 54, Folder 3)
        - Student Essays
          - 6th Grade (Box 54, Folder 4)
          - 8th Grade (Box 54, Folder 5)
          - 9th Grade (Box 54, Folder 6)
          - 10th Grade (Box 54, Folder 7)
          - 11th Grade (Box 54, Folder 8)
          - 12th Grade (Box 54, Folder 9)
        - Student Histories
          - 7th Grade (Box 54, Folder 10)
          - 8th Grade (Box 54, Folder 11)
          - 9th Grade (Box 54, Folder 12)
          - 10th Grade (Box 54, Folder 13)
          - 11th Grade (Box 54, Folder 14)
          - 12th Grade (Box 54, Folder 15)
        - Newsletters, Newspapers, and Clippings, 1948-1951 (Box 55, Folder 1)
        - Printed Material Received at Green Sea
          - 1942-1946 (Box 55, Folder 2)
          - 1947 (Box 55, Folder 3, Box 80)
          - 1947 (Box 55, Folder 4)
          - 1948 (Box 80, Box 55, Folder 5)
          - 1948-1949 (Box 55, Folder 6)
          - 1949-1955 (Box 80, Box 55, Folder 7)
          - 1954-1955 (Box 55, Folder 8, Box 81)
        - Material Related to Guidance in a Rural Community
          - Correspondence and Accompanying Material, 1951-1953 (Box 56, Folder 1)
          - Publicity. Columbia River Basin Project, 1952 (Box 56, Folder 2)
            In 1952 the Alliance for Guidance of Rural Youth gave a copy of Guidance in a Rural Community to a veteran who had won a free farm along the Columbia River in a contest sponsored by Columbia Valley business and civic organizations and the Veterans of Foreign Wars.
          - Photographs. Publicity for Columbia River Basin Project (Box 56, Folder 3)
          - Publicity, 1952-1953 (Box 56, Folder 4)
          - Reviews and Notices (Box 56, Folder 5)
          - Drafts of Article, Green Sea Project (Box 56, Folder 6)
          - Brochure (Box 56, Folder 7)
          - Introduction (Box 56, Folder 8)
          - Early Draft of Manuscript (Box 56, Folder 9)
          - Early Draft of Manuscript (Box 56, Folder 10)
          - Draft of Chapter 12 (Box 56, Folder 11)